{"data":{"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","address":"8950 Crane St","zipcode":"48213","owner":"Detroit Board of Education","licenseNumber":"035974","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","mostRecentLicenseDate":"5/13/2015","establishmentType":"Public School","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"Medium","reviewFrequencyDays":"210.0","geom":"0101000020E6100000C4636753F3C054C088F3865481324540","inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"43698","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","inspectionDate":"2018-09-27T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"137","pcount":"0","pfcount":"1","ccount":"5","criticalcount":"1","noncritical":"5","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"43698","inspectionDate":"9/27/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"4-301.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT for cooling and heating FOOD, and holding cold and hot FOOD, shall be sufficient in number and capacity to provide FOOD temperatures as required. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Inadequate","subProblem":"","location":"STEAM TABLE","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide additional equipment to meet requirement above."},{"inspectionid":"43698","inspectionDate":"9/27/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"6-202.15","violationDescription":"Outer openings of a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT shall be protected against the entry of insects and rodents. Unless otherwise allowed by law. \r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Outer opening(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided with","subProblem":"Screening that is sixteen mesh to the inch or greater","location":"OUTER DOOR(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace to meet requirements above."},{"inspectionid":"43698","inspectionDate":"9/27/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"inspectionid":"43698","inspectionDate":"9/27/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"6-501.111","violationDescription":"The presence of insects, rodents, and other pests shall be controlled to minimize their presence on the PREMISES.  by:\r\n(A) Routinely inspecting incoming shipments of FOOD and supplies; \r\n(B) Routinely inspecting the PREMISES for evidence of pests;\r\n(C) Using methods, if pests are found, such as trapping devices or other means of pest control as specified.(Pf) \r\n(D) Eliminating harborage conditions. \r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Pest(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Present in facility","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Remove pests from facility."},{"inspectionid":"43698","inspectionDate":"9/27/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN FREEZER","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"inspectionid":"43698","inspectionDate":"9/27/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"3-305.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination by storing the FOOD:\r\n(1)     In a clean, dry location;\r\n(2)     Where it is not exposed to splash, dust, or other contamination; and\r\n(3)     At least 15 cm (6 inches) above the floor, unless otherwise approved.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Food item(s) in storage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Exposed to dust, splash, or other contaminates","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN FREEZER","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Store in manner that does not contaminate items"}]},{"inspectionid":"42669","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","inspectionDate":"2018-06-19T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"95","pcount":"1","pfcount":"0","ccount":"0","criticalcount":"1","noncritical":"0","correctedcritical":"1","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"42669","inspectionDate":"6/19/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"7-201.11","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL shall be stored so they can not contaminate FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES by:   \r\n(A) Separating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL by spacing or partitioning; (P) and   \r\n(B) Locating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL in an area that is not above FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.  This paragraph does not apply to EQUIPMENT and UTENSIL cleaners and sanitizers that are stored in WAREWASHING areas for availability and convenience if the materials are stored to prevent contamination of FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES. (P)","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/with","subProblem":"Single-service/use items","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-19T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide adequate separation to prevent contamination."}]},{"inspectionid":"40712","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","inspectionDate":"2017-11-08T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"131","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"2","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"2","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"40712","inspectionDate":"11/8/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Equipment components","subItem":"seals","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"Torn","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"In the Cooler (milk)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Replace."},{"inspectionid":"40712","inspectionDate":"11/8/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All of the following food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American national standards institute, utilizing the conference for food protection standards:  (a) A food service establishment that is not any of the following:    (i) Operating under a temporary food service establishment license.  (ii) A vending machine location.     (b) An extended retail food establishment.  (c) Operated within a retail grocery.  (2) An individual certified under subsection (1) shall be recognized with full faith and credit by the state and all local units of government throughout the state.  (3) The department may promulgate rules to do all of the following:  (a) Develop requirements for retail food establishments to follow when employing certified food safety managers or personnel.  (b) Set a reasonable date for compliance with the requirements under subdivision (a) taking into consideration existing local personnel certification requirements.  (c) Establish certification fees necessary to implement, maintain, and track certified individuals directly or by contract. The department may annually adjust the schedule of fees to provide that the fee charged is sufficient to cover the cost of the certification tracking program.  (d) Implement and enforce the requirements described in subdivision (a).    (4) The certification program developed by the American national standards institute, as it exists on April 1, 2008 , is incorporated by reference. The department may adopt updates to the certification program accreditation standards in subsection (1) by rule.     (5) This section does not prohibit any local legislative body from implementing a food handler program, an employee health certification program, or a manager certification program, if it is not in conflict with this section.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"39404","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","inspectionDate":"2017-07-13T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"126","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"2","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"2","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"39404","inspectionDate":"7/13/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"5-205.15","violationDescription":"A PLUMBING SYSTEM shall be:\r\n(A) Repaired according to LAW; (P) and\r\n(B) Maintained in good repair.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Plumbing system","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Maintain in good repair"},{"inspectionid":"39404","inspectionDate":"7/13/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"6-501.111","violationDescription":"The presence of insects, rodents, and other pests shall be controlled to minimize their presence on the PREMISES.  by:\r\n(A) Routinely inspecting incoming shipments of FOOD and supplies; \r\n(B) Routinely inspecting the PREMISES for evidence of pests;\r\n(C) Using methods, if pests are found, such as trapping devices or other means of pest control as specified.(Pf) \r\n(D) Eliminating harborage conditions. \r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Routine inspections","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not performed","subProblem":"","location":"DRY STORAGE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Inspections must be performed as stated above."}]},{"inspectionid":"37132","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","inspectionDate":"2016-11-17T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"126","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"1","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"1","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"37132","inspectionDate":"11/17/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1643","name":"A. L. Holmes Elementary","violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"1643"}}